let quiz=[
    {
      question: "Which of the following statements is true for both Saturn and Jupiter :",
      option: [
           "Both rotate faster than the Earth",
           "Both rotate slower than the Earth",
           "Only one rotates rapily while the other rotates very slowly",
           "Their periods of rotation are linked to their period of revolution",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
  question: "Which type of star is maintained by the pressure of an electron gas?",
  option: [
  "Main Sequence Star",
  "White Dwarf",
  "Neutron Star",
  "Black Hole",
  ],
  answer: 2, 
},
    {
      question: "Which of the following is TRUE for Retrograde motion? Retrograde motion is :",
      option: [
           "caused by epicycles",
           "undergone only by superior planets",
           "undergone only by inferior planets",
           "an effect due to the projection of planet orbits onto the sky",
      ],
       answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "Beads of light visible around the rim of the moon at the beginning and end of a total solar eclipse are called :",
      option: [
           "Lunar Beads",
           "Solar Beads",
           "Baily's Beads",
           "Rim Beads",
      ],
      answer: 3,
    },
    {
      question: "The 2.7 Kelvin cosmic background radiation is concentrated in the :",
      option: [
           "radio wavelengths",
           "infrared",
           "visible",
           "ultraviolet",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "If you were watching a star collapsing to form a black hole, the light would disappear because it :",
      option: [
           "is strongly redshifted",
           "is strongly blueshifted",
           "its color suddenly becomes black",
           "none of these",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "In which spectral region is it possible for astronomers to observe through clouds ?",
      option: [
           "visual",
           "radio",
           "ultraviolet",
           "X-ray",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "The Magellanic Clouds are :",
      option: [
           "Irregular galaxies",
           "Spiral galaxies",
           "Elliptical galaxies",
           "Large clouds of gas and dust",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "The VISUAL aurora consists of luminous arcs, rays or bands in the night sky, usually confined to high latitudes and locate in the :",
      option: [
           "Troposphere",
           "Stratosphere",
           "Ozonosphere",
           "Ionosphere",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "This yellow-white, spectral F-type star is located in the constellation Carina south of the ecliptic. It ranks second in apparent brightness among the stars. Is this star :",
      option: [
           "Canopus",
           "Alpha Centauri",
           "Castor",
           "Rigel",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following first hypothesized that the Earth orbited the Sun ?",
      option: [
      "Alexander the Great",
      "Copernicus",
      "Socrates",
      "Tycho Brahe",
      ],
      answer: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "The Cosmic Background Radiation, a Remnant of the Big Bang, is at what temperature (K = Kelvin) ?",
      option: [
      "100 K",
      "0 K",
      "5.3 K",
      "2.7 K",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "The word ALBEDO refers to which of the following ?",
      option: [
      "The Wobbling motion of a Planet",
      "The amount of light a Planet reflects",
      "The Phase changes of a Planet",
      "The brightness Of a Star",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Cassini's Division is described by which of the following ?",
      option: [
      "A break in rings of Saturn",
      "A break in the clouds of Jupiter",
      "The distance between the first two Moons of Jupiter",
      "The distance between the Van Allen belts",
      ],
      answer: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "On February 9,1991 ,ROSAT, an orbiting observatory, finished the first ever all-sky survey of :",
      option: [
      "Gamma Rays",
      "Infrared Radiation",
      "Ultravioet Radiation",
      "X-ray",
      ],
      answer: 4,
    },
    ]
